Finding aid to the Dixon-Clark family papers. CA.MS.00368
Smith College Archives
Dixon-Clark family papers
1882-1950
1900-1945
Smith College Archives
Dixon-Clark family
CA.MS.00368
1.417 linear feet (3 containers)
The Dixon-Clark family papers contain photographs, newspaper articles, and correspondence regarding the private and social lives of various members of the family.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Dixon-Clark family papers were created over a number of years by various members of the Dixon-Clark family. The collection was given to the Smith College Archives by Ann Clark Eddins, Class of 1966.
Appraisal
Elizabeth Carron
Biographical / Historical
The Dixon-Clark family papers document several members of the Dixon-Clark family and in particular, three generations of Smith graduates.
Henry 'Harry' Austin Clark, Sr. (1865 - 1951) was one of the earliest stockholders of the Hawaiian Steamship Company, VP and Director of the Cuban-American Sugar Company, and Director of the Chaparra Sugar Company, Colonial Sugar Company, and the National Sugar Refining Company. In 1916, he and Elizabeth Marguerite Dixon married. Henry Austin Clark Jr. was born in 1917, followed shortly by Elizabeth Dixon Clark (Nicholas) in 1919.
Elizabeth 'Marguerite' Dixon Clark (1882 - 1942) served as President of the Class of 1906 during her time at Smith College. For several years she taught school in New York City before marrying Henry Austin Clark in 1916. After the birth of her two children, Marguerite continued to play a role in literary and social society. Until her death in 1942, Marguerite was active on several volunteer and philanthropic endeavors including serving on the Board of Directors for the Chistadora House (1925 - 1931) and with the Smith Club of Queens Borough.
Mary Newbury Dixon (1896 - 1978) graduated Smith College in 1917. The youngest sister of Marguerite, she also spent a year teaching school. She completed her Master of Landscape Architecture from the Cambridge School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture in 1934 after working several years as a draftsman and computational assistant for the New York Central Railroad.
Henry Austin 'Austie' Clark Jr. (1917 - 1991) attended Harvard in the late-1930s. After naval service during World War II, Clark and his wife Waleta settled into a life of automobile collecting, rallies and tours and raising a family. Clark's collection of cars led him to open the Long Island Automotive Museum (LIAM) in 1948. The museum's collection was moved to the Benson Ford Research Center at The Henry Ford in 1991.
Elizabeth 'Betty' Clark Nicholas (1919 - 1979) graduated Smith College in 1941. She married John Simmons Nicholas and moved to Greenwich, Connecticut.
Custodial History
Materials previously arranged and exhibited with the Henry Austin Clark Museum. The collection was transferred to the Smith College Archives in August, 2014.
Related Material
Researchers should also see materials within the following collections:
80. Class of 1906: Dixon, Elizabeth Marguerite 80. Class of 1917: Dixon, Mary Newbury 80. Class of 1941: Clark, Elizabeth Dixon 60. Cambridge School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture, 1919 - 1986 90. Smith Club of Queens Borough Henry Austin Clark, Jr. papers, Benson Ford Research Center, The Henry Ford Henry Austin Clark Library
Scope and Contents
The Dixon-Clark family papers are composed of a wide variety of documents relating to the family's personal history. The collection is heavily photographic; a wide sample of correspondence, personal journals, and writings are available.
black-and-white photographs; cyanotypes (photographic prints); direct positives; correspondence; Debutantes-United States; Depressions -- 1929 -- New York (State) -- New York; diaries; Receipts (acknowledgements); Upper class women - New York - Social life and customs.; Women college students-Massachusetts-Northampton.; World War, 1939 - 1945; Cambridge School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture; Clark, Elizabeth Marguerite, 1882 - 1942; Clark, Henry Austin, 1917-1991; Clark, Henry Austin, 1865 - 1952; Dixon, Mary Newbury, 1896 - 1978; Smith College -- Alumni and alumnae.; Smith College -- Campus.; Smith College -- Student life
- Elizabeth Dixon Clark
  - correspondence, 1925 - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Elizabeth Marguerite Dixon Clark
  - correspondence, 1900 - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - postcards, 1905 - 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - will, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The Forest Playmates", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - poetry, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - poetry collections, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "If You Only Had One More Year", undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Henry Austin Clark, Jr.
  - correspondence, 1940 - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Henry Austin Clark, Sr.
  - correspondence, 1890 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - diary, 1916 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - general, 1890 - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Photographs and Ephemera
  - Elizabeth Dixon Clark, 1919 - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Henry Austin Clark, Jr., 1917 - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Henry Austin Clark, Sr., 1915 - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth Marguerite Dixon Clark, 1900 - 1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - general (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Artifacts
  - pin, National Gun Association, undated (Box 3)
  - pocketknife, undated (Box 3)
  - portrait, around 1910 (Box 3)
  - pin, Smith College Alumnae Association, around 1920 (Box 3)